Alumni Directories UP009
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Alumni Directories
1852 -- 2008
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Alumni Relations
Tufts University Alumni Association
UP009
0.25 Linear Feet
37 Volumes
1 Artifact(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of bound, printed volumes, the first one dating to 1912, listing alumni of Tufts, usually by class year. Indices and cross references are usually provided. Prior to 1950 volumes listed all alumni, faculty and administrative staff, living and dead. After 1950, only living members of the Tufts community are listed. Personal information beyond name and graduation year is usually limited to current address and occupation.
Certain directories are specifically geared for the alumni of particular schools, such as Medical, Dental, Fletcher, or Engineering. There are also thematic directories such as international alumni and Asian alumni.
The first lists of students were printed in the college bulletin each year. These lists indicated only active students in each of the classes for that particular year. The first attempt to comprehensively list alumni of Tufts was in 1896 when the class of 1897 published "A History of Tufts College, 1854-1896." In addition to being a short history of the institution, it also listed all graduates as well as faculty. Other compendia of alumni followed, usually produced by the administration. Until 1950 these volumes listed all graduates, living and dead. Beginning with the 1950 "Directory of Tufts College Alumni" the directory was produced by the Alumni Council and now listed only living alumni and administrative and teaching staff. However, each edition of the directory also contained a "necrology" listing those who had died since the previous edition.
- Alumni Directories, 1852 -- 2008; 1912 -- 2000; UP009.001; 0.25 Linear Feet; 37 Volumes; 1 Artifact(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains bound, printed volumes, the first one dating to 1912, listing alumni of Tufts, usually by class year. Indices and cross references are usually provided. Prior to 1950 volumes listed all alumni, faculty and administrative staff, living and dead. After 1950, only living members of the Tufts community are listed. Personal information beyond name and graduation year is usually limited to current address and occupation. The first lists of students were printed in the college bulletin each year. These lists indicated only active students in each of the classes for that particular year. The first attempt to comprehensively list alumni of Tufts was in 1896 when the class of 1897 published "A History of Tufts College, 1854-1896." In addition to being a short history of the institution, it also listed all graduates as well as faculty. Other compendia of alumni followed, usually produced by the administration. Until 1950 these volumes listed all graduates, living and dead. Beginning with the 1950 "Directory of Tufts College Alumni" the directory was produced by the Alumni Council and now listed only living alumni and administrative and teaching staff. However, each edition of the directory also contained a "necrology" listing those who had died since the previous edition.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Tufts College Register of Officers of Instruction and Government and Directory of Graduates, 1852 -- 1905; UP009.001.001.001 (Box Volume 1)
  - The Book of Tufts People, 1857 -- 1941; UP009.001.002.001 (Box Volume 2)
  - Directory of Tufts College Alumni, 1950; UP009.001.003.001 (Box Volume 3)
  - History of Tufts College, 1854 -- 1896; UP009.001.004.001 (Box Volume 4)
    This book was published by the class of 1897 to communicate the history of the College as well as list former students.
  - Tufts Directory of Lawyers, 1948; UP009.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Register of Alumni and Officers, 1917; UP009.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Register of Alumni and Officers, 1923; UP009.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Directory of Graduates, 1929; UP009.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Tufts Alumni and Staff in World War II, 1945; UP009.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Supplement to Directory, 1945; UP009.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Directory of Alumni, New York City area, 1966; UP009.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Jackson College Association of Tufts Alumnae, 1969 -- 1970; UP009.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Tufts University Alumni Directory, 1969; UP009.001.006.001 (Box Volume 6)
  - Tufts University Alumni Directory, 1974; UP009.001.007.001 (Box Volume 7)
  - Tufts University Alumni Directory, 1983; UP009.001.008.001 (Box Volume 8)
  - Tufts University Alumni Directory, 1989; UP009.001.009.001 (Box Volume 9)
  - Tufts University Alumni Directory, 1994; UP009.001.010.001 (Box Volume 10)
  - Tufts Asian Alumni Directory, 1995 -- 1996; UP009.001.011.001 (Box Volume 11)
  - Tufts International Directory, 1996; UP009.001.012.001 (Box Volume 12)
  - Tufts University Alumni Directory, 2000; UP009.001.013.001 (Box Volume 13)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1933 -- 1971; UP009.001.014.001 (Box Volume 14)
  - Tufts College Register of Officers of Instruction and Government and Directory of Graduates, 1912; UP009.001.015.001 (Box Volume 15)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1977; UP009.001.016.001 (Box Volume 16)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1978 -- 1979; UP009.001.017.001 (Box Volume 17)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1980 -- 1981; UP009.001.018.001 (Box Volume 18)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1983 -- 1984; UP009.001.019.001 (Box Volume 19)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1987; UP009.001.020.001 (Box Volume 20)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1990 -- 1991; UP009.001.021.001 (Box Volume 21)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1992 -- 1993; UP009.001.022.001 (Box Volume 22)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1995 -- 1996; UP009.001.023.001 (Box Volume 23)
  - Tufts University School of Medicine Centennial Alumni Directory, 1993; UP009.001.024.001 (Box Volume 24)
  - Tufts University School of Medicine Alumni Directory, 1983; UP009.001.025.001 (Box Volume 25)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine Alumni Directory, 1983; UP009.001.026.001 (Box Volume 26)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine Alumni Directory, 1988; UP009.001.027.001 (Box Volume 27)
  - Tufts University School of Medicine Alumni Directory, 1988; UP009.001.028.001 (Box Volume 28)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine Alumni Directory, 1993; UP009.001.029.001 (Box Volume 29)
  - Tufts University Engineering Alumni Directory, 1957; UP009.001.030.001 (Box Volume 30)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Directory of Alumni, 1976; UP009.001.031.001 (Box Volume 31, Box Shared 10)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine Alumni Directory, 2003; UP009.001.032.00001 (Box Volume 32)
  - Tufts University School of Medicine Alumni and Faculty Directory, 2000; UP009.001.033.00001 (Box Volume 33)
  - Tufts College Register, 1852 -- 1905; UP009.001.034.00001 (Box 34)
  - Tufts College Register, 1852 -- 1917; UP009.001.034.00002 (Box 34)
  - Tufts University School of Dental Medicine Alumni Directory, 1998; UP009.001.035.00001 (Box Volume 35)
  - Tufts University Alumni Directory, 2006; UP009.001.036.00001 (Box Volume 36)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 1999; UP009.001.037.00001 (Volume Volume 37)
    directories
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 2008; UP009.001.038.00001 (Volume Volume 38)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy Directory of Alumni, 2003; UP009.001.039.00001 (Volume Volume 39)
  - Tufts University Engineering Alumni Directory Record of Deaths of Engineers, 1957; UP009.001.040.00001 (Box Volume 40)